Out of the worst nightmare!
Bug is a science fiction, horror, mystery film directed by Jeannot Szwarc.
An earthquake releases a strain of mutant cockroaches with the ability to start
fires, which proceed to cause destructive chaos in a small town.
The studies carried out by scientist James Parmiter, however, reveal
an intent with much more far-reaching consequences.
Prof. James Parmiter, played by Bradford Dillman.
Carrie Parmiter, played by Joanna Miles.
Gerald Metbaum, played by Richard Gilliland.
Norma Tacker, played by Jamie Smith-Jackson.
Prof. Mark Ross, played by Alan Fudge.
Tom Tacker, played by Jesse Vint.
Bug is a 1975 American science fiction horror film directed by Jeannot Szwarc and written by
William Castle and Thomas Page, from Page's novel The Hephaestus Plague (1973).
Shot in Panavision, it was the last film Castle was
involved in before his death in 1977.
The film starred Bradford Dillman, Joanna Miles and Richard Gilliland.
The film initially depicts a new insect species, which faces extinction.
Professor James Parmiter, a widowed scientist crossbreeds the species with
cockroaches, creating a sentient hybrid species of insects.
The film explores themes of fire, based on novel
or book, insect, mutation, mutant.
The tone is intense and dark and thought_provoking.